前情提要
Previously on Class of '09...
（过去）
泰约 你自己测试过吗
Tayo, did you self-test?
-报告长官 有 -你通过了
Yes, sir, I did. And you passed?
-是的 长官 -但你在这里没有通过测验
Yes, ma'am. Well, you haven't passed it here.
我不在乎你们喜不喜欢对方
I don't care whether you like each other or not.
当你受到攻击时
These are the people who'll be by your side
-这些人会在你身边 -现在他们在监视我
when you're under fire. Now they're watching me.
（未来）
你应该跟乌尔谈谈 只有她
You should talk to Hour. She's the only one
了解那些程式码
who ever understood the code.
（现在）
-你们来访的目的是  -我们只是
Why are you here? We were just
希望能聊一聊
hoping that we could talk a bit.
我看到报导 胡佛局长会流放 他不喜欢的探员到标特和比林斯员
I read that J. Edgar Hoover used to exile out-of-favor agents to Butte and Billings.
麦可斯探员 你犯了什么错吗
Did you do something wrong, Agent Michaels?
地下室
The basement.
（妻子）
我们阻止了对方的行动
Did we stop something?
还是启动了
Or start it?
如果你怕了 尽管举手 我就会停车
If you get scared, just raise your hand and I'll stop.
汽车和联邦调查局一起成长
The car and the Bureau grew up together.
调查局成立于1908年
The Bureau Of Investigation was founded in 1908.
同一年 亨利福特开始在底特律
That same year, Henry Ford began mass production
皮凯特大道工厂大量生产T型车
of the Model T automobile at the Piquette Avenue Plant in Detroit.
有史以来第一次 一般的美国家庭
For the first time ordinary American families
买得起自己的车子
could afford their own car.
有史以来第一次 一般的美国罪犯也买得起车了
For the first time ordinary American criminals could, too.
没有汽车 本局会变成怎样
What would the Bureau have become without the car?
它会有任何的变化吗
Would it have become anything at all?
赛道已清空 可进行高速转向操驾
AGENT (over P.A.): Track is clear for spin maneuver.
好 我出发了
Okay. Here we go.
你太紧绷了
You're too high-strung.
加油
Come on, come on.
你很拼 这样很好
You've got some fight. I like that.
但要倒车甩尾直行 你必须让车子有点失控
But to do a J-turn, you've got to lose control.
太好了
Yes!
很好
Yeah!
联邦凶杀案
第一季第三集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
好好监视 盯住那些窗户
We've got line of sight on both sides of the building.
（现在 2023年）
他在图皮瑞克的牧场 我们包围住他了
He was at Two Bricks Ranch. We've got him surrounded.
他想要谈判
He wants to negotiate.
破门小队 现在就位
Breach team, moving into position now.
就位
Positions!
AB两队已就位
Alpha, Bravo Team's in position.
不要开枪 嘿
No one fire. Hey!
注意 牛仔走进去了
Heads up, got one walking in.
-走到栏杆旁 -收到
联调局 把手举起来
FBI! Keep your hands in the air!
马克图皮瑞克在哪里
Where is Mark Tupirik?
你根本不了解接下来会发生什么事
You got no idea what's coming.
（未来 2034年）
（电子讯号阻断器）
（警告 侦测到磁干扰）
Warning. Magnetic interference detected.
（警告 侦测到磁…）
妈妈
Mama!
我想要你见见我的家人
I want you to meet my family.
你们好 我是波伊特
Hi, I'm Poet.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
-她是莎拉 -你好
This is Sara. Hello there.
你为什么看起来这么悲伤
Why do you look so sad?
我不悲伤 我很开心
I-I'm not sad. I'm happy.
你是我妈的朋友吗
Are you my mom's friend?
她是我最好的朋友
She was my best friend.
我需要你的帮忙
I need your help.
我的帮忙
My help?
你是对的
You were right.
-我错了 -错在哪里
I was wrong. What were you wrong about?
全部
All of it.
他们偷了你的系统 把它变成了可怕的东西
They stole your system. They turned it into something terrible.
我告诉过你会发生这种事
I told you this would happen.
我别无选择 由不得我决定
I didn't have a choice. It wasn't my call--
你有选择 你可以相信我
You did have a choice. You could've trusted me.
再也不是预测了 它已成真 现在正在发生
It's not a prediction anymore. Okay? It's reality. It's happening now.
发生了什么事
What is happening?
-阿莫斯贾西亚死了 -很好
- Amos Garcia is dead. - Good!
让他腐烂 他偷了我的系统 你站在他那一边
Let him rot. He stole my fucking system. You sided with him.
他中枪时我在场 他给了我一样东西
I was there when he was shot. He gave me something.
我需要你帮忙解读
Something that I need your help understanding.
这个系统已经扩展到 我们生活的每个层面
The system has expanded into every part of our lives.
先前我恳求你帮我
I begged you to help me.
我从来没有求过你任何事
I've never asked you for anything.
当我恳求你 你却转身拒绝我
And I begged you. And you turned your back on me.
我了解你 诗人 我知道在我对你告白之后
I know you, Poet. I know it would've been too intimate for you if...
如果你还站在我这边的话 对你来说会太过亲密
...if you had sided with me after I told you that I was in love with you.
这个嘛…
Well...
就是这样了
here we are.
我来到这里
Here I am.
蒙羞 独自一人
Humiliated, alone.
我失去调查局 我失去最好的朋友 我无法改变这些事
I lost the Bureau, I lost my best friend. And I can't change any of it,
但我可以试 我可以试着弥补错误
but I can try. I can try and make this right.
（现在）
我们称它为“更好的明天”
We call it "Better Tomorrow."
在你看来 更好的明天是什么样子
What does a better tomorrow look like to you?
那是一个坏事都不会被遗漏
It's a world where nothing bad gets missed.
证据都不会被忽视的世界
And no piece of evidence is ever overlooked.
听起来很不错
I like the sound of that.
你不觉得20年后 他们会在我们变得正聪明的时候
Don't you think it's crazy that after 20 years,
把我们踢出去 这样很蠢吗
they kick us out just as we're getting smart?
-对 会啊 -我们一直致力于学习
Yeah, I do. All that time we devote to learning.
现在 如果所有的人生经验 所有的智慧
Now what if all that life experience, all that wisdom,
都保留在这里呢
was held here?
你是这么看的吗
That's how you see this?
当本局在调查大学航空炸弹客的案子
When the Bureau was investigating the Unabomber case,
他们引进了 z索引电脑系统 你记得吗
they introduced the Z Index computer system. Do you remember that?
没有人记得z索引系统
Nobody remembers the Z Index system.
那是调查局最早使用的电脑系统
It was one of the first computer systems the Bureau ever used.
保留了1100万份大学航空炸弹客文件 8400万个人名
Held all 11 million Unabomber case documents. 84 million names.
探员就不用再到成堆的箱子里翻找
So agents didn't have to search through stacks of boxes anymore.
调查局在一夜之间改变
The Bureau changed overnight.
-这不只是档案系统 -这是探员的图书馆
This is more than just a filing system. It's a library of special agents.
汇集了你跟我的精华
It's the best of you. It's the best of me.
这是梦想
It's the dream.
我不懂为何联调局会拒绝
I don't understand why the Bureau would say no.
采用这项科技就代表整个调查程序
Adopting this technology would mean entire investigations
不会依赖某个探员的判断或记忆
don't depend on one agent's judgment... or their memory.
我们可以回放任何的访谈
You could play back any interview.
参考任何的案件 即使你正在外调查也是一样
Reference any case. Even if you're in the field.
这是防止偏见和错误的护栏
It's a guardrail against bias and error.
好
Okay.
你觉得乌尔为什么 这么执着于局里的科技
Why do you think Hour is so fixated on the Bureau's technology?
我才刚跟你解释过原因
I just told you why.
动机…
Motivations...
可能很复杂
...can be complicated.
你要扯到哪里去
Where are you going with this?
（性倾向与压抑性格 不可预测性）
-现在又不是1960年代 -这不是批判
-This isn't the 1960s. - It's not a judgment.
-看起来就是 -这是洞见
- It certainly looks like one. - It's an insight.
乌尔的技术透露了她什么事
What would Hour's tech say about her?
透露出她非常关切公平与正义
It would say that she cares deeply about fairness and justice.
或者她对科技的信赖程度超过人类
Or that she trusts technology more than she trusts people.
或许她想为其他人 创造一个公平的世界
May-Maybe she wants to create a fairer world
而那个世界对她来说比较好
for others than that world has-has been for her.
我觉得听起来很棒 有什么…
That sounds great to me. What does...
如果这是她的动机又有什么关系
what does it matter if that's her motivation?
太过于私人了
It's deeply personal.
这不只是份提案 它深植于她的认同里
This isn't just a proposal. It's, it's... it's rooted in her identity.
理想如此深化 是很难放手的
When ideas go that deep, it's hard to let it go.
如果她无法改革调查局
If she can't reform the Bureau, she...
她可能会感受到比拒绝更深层的创伤
she might feel a kind of trauma that goes deeper than rejection.
这种事以前发生过 诗人
It's happened before, Poet.
我知道你晓得那些名字 我不必举出来
I know you know the names, I don't need to name them.
你不是要我回报她的技术
You didn't want me to report back on her tech.
你是要我在你关闭她的计画时 管理好她的情绪
You wanted me to manage her emotions if you shut her down.
她知道所有的秘密 诗人 她花了十年的时间搜集
She knows all of the secrets, Poet. She spent ten years collecting them.
你知道好笑的是什么吗 调查局声称
You know what's funny, the Bureau claims to want different types
要找具有不同经验的各类人士
of people with different experiences
却只要我们做该死的同一件事
so long as we all do the same fucking thing.
这个机构不是一张白纸 诗人
This institution isn't a blank page, Poet.
我没办法改写 其他人也是
I don't get to rewrite it, nor does anyone else.
1985年 本局创立了暴力犯罪逮捕计画
In 1985, the Bureau pioneered the Violent Criminal Apprehension Program.
这个计画的起点 是一套叫做VACS 11785的系统
ViCAP started on a system called the Vax 11/785.
大小跟这个房间差不多
It was the size of this room.
纳扎里探员 今天的听证会不是要谈过去的计画
Agent Nazari, today's hearing isn't about programs from the past--
过去是这次讨论内容的核心
The past is at the heart of what we're talking about.
重点在于保留知识 而不是让它溜走
It's about holding on to knowledge, rather than letting it slip away.
一个中央知识库
A central repository
记录了每次的犯罪调查
of every criminal investigation,
全国各地的每个探员都能存取
accessible by every agent in every part of the country.
在1985年是个高明的点子 但当时我们弃而不用
It was a brilliant idea in 1985. And we betrayed it then.
我们不能重蹈覆辙
We can't betray it again.
这个房间里的每个人 都能说出至少一名受害者
Every person in this room could name at least one victim who would still be alive today
如果执法人员把线索串连起来 这个人在今天还会活着
if law enforcement had connected the dots. You can appreciate how our agents
你可以理解探员有多么不想被监视
don't want to be spied on?
-我可以理解 是的 -你会让监视变成
I can appreciate that, yes. You-you would make spying a matter of-of what?
例行公事 每次的对话
Routine? Every conversation?
-不 这样说不公平… -抱歉 不好意思
Well, no, that's, that's an unfair character-- Excuse me, I'm sorry,
我们预测
but we predicted this would create
这会让本局面临招不到人的空前危机
a recruitment crisis of the kind the Bureau's never seen.
我们不能这么害怕 可能会得罪人的技术
We can't be so scared of technology treading on our toes
因此就认定它无用
that we render it useless.
今天 暴力犯罪逮捕计画 保存的资料还不到所有暴力犯罪的1%
Today ViCAP holds less than one percent of all violent crimes.
档案里应该要有超过五百万个案子 它却只有大约九万件
There should be over five million cases on file. It has around 90,000.
这个资料库搜集一切的资讯 无论那重不重要
Your database collects everything, whether it's important or not.
我们要搜集到了 才会知道什么是重要的
We don't know what's important until we collect it.
是啊 好吧
Yeah, okay.
这个论点…让人们担心
That rationale worries people.
你提议的是自动化搜索
What you're proposing is an industrial trawler.
我们有探员 那是我们训练出来 也是我们信赖的人
We have agents who we train and-and who we trust...
这不是建立在不信任上面的资料库
This is not a database built on mistrust.
这是探员们的累积智慧
It's the accumulated wisdom of the agents
来自诸多前辈和我现在的同事
who've served before me and who serve today.
它不是要取代或监视他们 而是把他们连结起来
It doesn't replace them or spy on them. It connects them.
-探员一直都在做判断 -它比我们聪明
The agent always makes the judgments. It's smarter than us, faster than us,
比我们快 比我们公平
fairer than us.
纳扎里探员 这不是你的论点吗
Isn't that your contention, Agent Nazari?
我的论点是 它协助我们 变得更聪明 更快 也更公平
My contention is that it helps us become smarter and faster and fairer.
我需要喝一杯
I need a drink.
他们会在月底关闭这里
They're shutting us down at the end of the month.
这不是你们的错 你们表现杰出
It's not your fault. You did extraordinary work.
只是我们的时运不济
It wasn't our time.
我很骄傲…
I'm proud...
嫌犯马克图皮瑞克 拥有强大火力 极度危险
Suspect Mark Tupirik is heavily armed and extremely dangerous.
收到 你可以走了
Copy that. Move on.
可以走了 往前开
Go ahead. You can go.
往前 快点
Move up! Come on!
你们要去哪里
Where you guys heading?
只是要去送个货
Just making a delivery.
请靠边停
Pull in, please.
（建设公司 土木工程与混凝土专家）
这些人没问题
These guys are good.
图皮瑞克人在哪里
Where's Tupirik now?
他要去哪里
Where's he going?
他打算何时发动攻击
What's he planning to attack?
我们可以整天坐在这里
We can sit here all day.
获准再审问他24小时
Been granted another 24 hours to question him.
太好了 再多24小时 他也只是不发一语
Mm, great. Another 24 hours of him saying nothing.
-我们有什么损失  -不可以 长官
- What have we got to lose? - No way, sir.
那是华府想要从中央 细部管理每个外地办公室
It's D.C. trying to micromanage every field office from the center.
对 但我们在追的人 拥有比我们精良的电脑
Yeah, but the people we're chasing, they've got better computers than we do.
如果总部启动那个资料库 它将取代我们
If HQ rolls that database, it will replace us.
还有我的上级 我是说真的
And then above me, too. I'm telling you.
你打开那个盒子 就永远无法再阖上
You open that box, you'll never be able to close it.
你真是救星 长官
You're a lifesaver, sir.
喝过之后再说
Don't say that yet, until you taste it.
-来 给你 -我相信一定好喝
- Here you go, man. - I'm sure it's great.
-非常感谢 -好 谢谢你
- I really appreciate it. - All right, thank you.
-非常感谢 祝你今天顺心 -好的
- Thank you so much. You have a good day. - All right.
（西北山电力公司）
去你的
Fuck you!
-我很好… -是 但我不好
I'm okay. I'm okay. Yeah, but I'm not okay.
玻璃是怎么回事
Tell me about the glass.
我们面临威胁
There were threats.
-好 什么时候  -一直都有威胁
- Okay, when? - There've always been threats
从我们搬来这里之后
from the moment that we got here.
你怎么什么都没说
Why didn't you say something?
因为我不想让他们进我们的脑袋里
Because I didn't want them to get in our heads.
亲爱的 我以前就面临过死亡威胁
Baby, I've had death threats before.
对 听我说 我…
Okay. Okay.
我以前没想过我会跟任何人共度一生
I never imagined that I'd spend my life with anyone.
现在 我没有办法想象没有你的人生
And now, I can't imagine my life without you.
但保护我不受世界威胁不是你的工作
But it's not your job to protect me from the world.
那是我唯一的工作
That's my only job.
如果做不到这点 这一切有何意义
What's the point of all this if I can't do that?
如果让我们觉得安全的唯一方法 是我辞职…
If the only way that we can feel safe is for me to quit... you say the word.
-你只要开口 -那你要做什么
And what would you do, hmm? I don't know.
我不知道 照顾孩子
Look after the kids?
我们没有孩子
We don't have any kids.
薇 我向上帝发誓…
Viv, I swear to God, I swear to God,
如果你要我辞职
if you need me to quit,
我就会辞职
then I'll quit.
对不起…
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
真的对不起 亲爱的
I'm so sorry, baby.
你早知道会有这次的袭击
You knew about the attack!
什么袭击
What attack?
你的朋友死了 我太太还活着
Your friends are dead, my wife is still alive,
我们会再次从头审问你
and we are going to start this interview again.
-那些人拒绝使用它 -对 你的人曾经有机会
The men refuse to use it. Yeah, well, your men had the chance.
我必须跟纳扎里探员谈谈
I need to speak to Special Agent Nazari.
-喔 嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
-你好吗 你的气色很不错 -不 你的气色才好
- Look at you. Oh, you look amazing. - Well, you look amazing.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
很高兴再见到你 波伊特
Good to see you again, Poet.
我也是 你们家太漂亮了
You, too. Um, your house is... amazing.
别管房子了 妈 爸
Forget the house. Mom? Pop?
来 我要你们见见波伊特
Yeah. I want you to meet Poet.
-你好 可以抱你一下吗  -你好
- Hi. Can I give you a hug?
-当然 -真高兴见到你
- Of course. - It's so nice to meet you.
天啊 不敢相信这是你们第一次见面
Oh, my God. I can't believe this is the first time you're meeting.
-我也很高兴见到你 -他们应该要在
- Nice to meet you as well. - They were supposed
我的毕业典礼上见面 但我爸妈来不了
to meet at my, uh, graduation, but they couldn't make it.
但还好他们能来参加订婚派对
But fortunately, they're here at the engagement party.
纳扎里夫妇 你们的女儿 是我在这个世界上最喜欢的人
Mr. and Mrs. Nazari, your daughter is my favorite person in the world.
-你能这样说真是太好了 -波伊特只说好话
What a nice thing to say. Poet only ever says nice things.
-摄影师要找我们 -好
- The photographer needs us. - Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
-幸会 -我也是
- Nice to meet you. - You, too.
-我再找你 -去吧
- I'll find you. - Go, go.
谢谢
Thank you.
茱儿
Drew.
我不知道你要来
Hey. I didn't know you were coming.
乌尔希望这成为惊喜
Hour wanted it to be a surprise.
当她邀请我 我是有点惊讶
When she invited me, I was kind of surprised.
-你还在任教吗  -最后一年了
- Um, are you... are you still teaching? - It's my last year.
学员怎么样
What are the trainees like?
你们是我们教过最好的一班
You were our best class.
少来 我相信 你对所有的学生都这样说
Come on. I'm sure you say that to all the students.
不 我是真的很以你们两个为荣
No. I'm really, really proud of you two.
你们是我职涯中的最大亮点
You were the highlight of my career.
-嘿 -嘿
Hey. Hey.
开心的时候竟然没找我
No having fun without me.
来干杯吧
A toast.
干杯
茱儿 如果你不介意的话 我想找她跳支舞
If you don't mind, Drew, I'd like to steal her for a dance.
请便
Be my guest.
-可以吗  -我以为你永远不会问
- May I? - I thought you'd never ask.
诗人 我知道他们派你来监视我
Poet, I know that they sent you to spy on me.
你怎么猜出来的
How did you guess?
当他们建议我跟你一起工作时
When they suggested I work with you.
我拒绝了 但他们说会找其他人
I told them "no," but they said that they would find someone else.
不 我很高兴是你
No. I'm happy it was you.
我想让你看到我创造出来的系统
I wanted you to see what I created.
我以它为傲
I'm proud of it.
我也很骄傲
I'm proud, too.
他们到底在担心什么
What are they so fucking worried about?
太冒犯了
It's offensive.
你打算怎么办  现在他们要关闭你的计画
What are you gonna do now that they've shut you down?
我会辞职
I'll quit.
泰约打来的
It's Tayo.
-我是乌尔 -你好 乌尔 是我
- This is Hour. - Hey, Hour, it's me.
我知道…
Hey, I know that it's, uh...
我们已经很久没有讲过话了 但是…
it's been a long time since we last spoke, but, uh...
我想要知道你那个程式的所有细节
I need to know everything about your program.
它的作用以及方法
What it does, how it does it.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我的名字
My name?
在你思考的时候 有个名字你一定知道
While you think about that, there's a name you do know.
马克图皮瑞克在哪里
Where is Mark Tupirik?
图皮瑞克
Tupirik?
-图皮瑞克在哪里  -对 他在哪里
- Where is Tupirik? - Yes. Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
或许他躲在桌子底下 我应该看一眼吗
Maybe he's under the table? Shall I look?
他不在
Not there.
有个概念是这样 不管我们多么努力
Here's a notion. No matter how hard we try,
有时候就因为我们非常努力
sometimes because of how hard we try,
到了最后
in the end,
我们总是会暴露自己
we always reveal ourselves.
他在做什么
What's he doing?
什么事也没做
Nothing.
他这样子多久了
How long has he been doing it for?
六小时了
Six hours.
嘿
Hey.
我们没有获得授权
We don't have authorization.
-你想要关掉它  -重点不是我想要什么
- You want to shut this down? - It's not about what I want.
-让我拿到许可之后再继续 -我们没时间了
- Let me get approval to continue. - We don't have time.
-这件事正在发生 -我们不被允许
- This is happening right now. - We're not allowed.
-“允许”  -对 我们不被允许
- Allowed? - No, we are not allowed.
你想要做什么
What are you trying to do?
我不会关掉 这个有史以来最强大的调查工具
I'm not gonna shut down the most powerful investigative tool ever created
我们可是正在调查这个国家前所未见
in the middle of an investigation into one of the most dangerous men
最危险的人物
this country has ever seen.
如果他们想终止这件事 可以派一支队伍来
If they want to pull the plug, they can send in a team.
他们已经派了 那支队伍就是我
They did. The team is me.
那的确是跟你想要的事情有关
Then it is about what you want?
泰约 我是乌尔 以下是一些可能符合的项目
Tayo, this is Hour. A list of possible matches:
教派…
a religious cult,
汽水品牌…
a brand of soda,
建设公司
a construction company...
A construction company.
（我们逮到你了）
六点钟方向 我们走
Six, let's move.
过去那里搜集你能找到的任何东西
Right over there. Collect anything you can find.
-这里也是 -知道了
- Same over here. - All clear.
一切安全
楼下 安全
没有 这里没东西
Negative. Nothing here.
（TCS建设公司）
有图皮瑞克的线索了
We've got a lead on Tupirik.
我们追踪到一辆建设公司拥有的卡车
We're tracking a truck owned by that construction company.
（盥洗室）
联调局 趴到地上 手举起来
FBI! Down on the ground!
准许开枪
Clear to shoot!
一人倒下了
Got one down!
找到了
Got him!
州警 手举起来
State Police! Let's see your hands!
我没有武器…
I'm not armed, I'm not armed!
不要动
Don't move.
慢一点 过来
Easy. Come on.
-嘿 -嘿
Hey. - Hey.
-亲爱的 -什么
- Baby, we got him. - What?
我们抓到他了 终于抓到他了
We fucking got him!
-天啊 -是
- Oh, my God. - Yeah.
我的天哪
Oh, thank God.
他们要派飞机
They sent in a plane.
调查局要派出一架私人飞机 他们要我去审问他
The Bureau's sending a private jet. They want me to interrogate him.
等等 为什么是你
I mean, why does, why does it have to be you?
要不然还会有谁
Who else could it be?
（未来）
你还在开特斯拉
Still driving the Tesla.
这是经典车
It's a classic.
（感谢您没开车）
-所以 家里有谁  -你说的“谁”是指
So, who's at home? What do you mean who?
伴侣
A partner?
没有人 没有
No one. No.
我…我试过了 但是…
Well, I-I tried, but...
当他们走进房间
I never felt that...
我从来没有感受到那股激动 你懂吗
flutter when they walked in the room, you know?
是 我懂
Yeah, I know.
而且 有时候
Plus, sometimes
跟不对的人在一起 比自己一个人还寂寞
being with the wrong person is more lonely than being without them.
你的车正在跟警察提到我们
Your car is talking about us to the police.
这附近一定有检查点
There must be a checkpoint nearby.
它说了什么
What's it saying?
我们去过哪里 现在要去哪里
Where we've been. Where we're going.
-我们是谁 -我们是谁
- Who we are. - Who are we?
两名女性 没有前科 携带一把有证枪枝
Two women. No prior criminal record. Carrying one licensed firearm.
没有正当理由的话 不应该分享资讯
It's not supposed to share information without reasonable cause.
-他们有正当理由 -什么理由
- They have reasonable cause. - What's that?
你在开车
You're driving.
州警已经控制这辆车 请保持冷静
State Police have taken control of this car. Please remain calm.
这里是安全检查点 请待在车内
This is a security checkpoint. Please remain in your vehicle.
请把枪枝放进手套箱里
Please place your firearm in the glove compartment.
-波伊特探员 -警官 有什么事吗
Special Agent Poet. Officer, how can I help you?
可以问一下你为什么在开车吗
May I ask why you're driving?
我喜欢开车
I like to drive.
（警告 潜在嫌犯）
你可以离开了
You're free to go.
（感谢您没开车）
局里无法让电脑重新开机 他们被封锁了
The Bureau couldn't reboot the computers. They were locked out.
他临死前把这东西交给我
He gave this to me right before he died.
这个跟你创造的系统有何差异
How is this different than what you created?
我创造的是犯罪资料库
I created a criminal database.
它搜集资讯然后呈现给我们
It collected information and presented it to us.
-所有的思考都是我们做的 -像是图书馆
All of the thinking was done by us. It was a library.
这个系统会自己建立连结
This system is making connections on its own.
我没有看到任何由探员发出的指令
I don't see any commands being issued by agents.
我看到凭空出现的互动线
I see new lines of interactions coming out of nowhere.
它不需要人
It doesn't need people?
它需要有关人的资料 但没错 它不需要人
It needs data about people. But no, it does not need people.
这是跟我们截然不同的智慧
This is an intelligence nothing like our own.
它有什么能耐
What is it capable of?
波伊特探员
Special Agent Poet...
你一直被蒙蔽
You've been lied to.
这个系统能自行运作
The system is acting on its own.
决定有罪和无罪 进行预测性逮捕
Deciding guilt and innocence. Making predictive arrests.
你必须调查泰约真正知道的事
You must investigate what Tayo really knows.
（现在）
想说来听听吗
You want to share?
你以为你逮到我了
Oh, you think you caught me.
我是逮到你了
I have caught you.
但这里正是我想待的地方
But I'm exactly where I want to be.
被关在这里 真的吗
Oh, locked up in here? Really?
最好的观众席
Best seat in the house.
好吧 为什么
Okay. Why is that?
因为我可以看清楚 你听到消息时脸上的表情
'Cause I get to see the expression on your face when you hear the news.
什么消息
What news?
What news?!
我从没想过…
I never imagined...
“从没想过”
Never imagined?
你还在这里
You'd still be here.
我也没想到
I didn't either.
这些年我错过了什么
Where are the years I missed?
我很高兴你在
I'm happy you're here.
我也是
I'm happy, too.
你一定累了
You must be tired.
-晚安 诗人 -晚安
Good night, Poet. Good night.
字幕翻译：江霸子